Guide to the Yale Divinity School Faculty Writings and Publications
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Faculty M-W
  - Outka, Gene
    - Universal Love and Impartiality. The Love Commandments: Essays in Christian Ethics and Moral Philosophy, Edmund N. Santurri and William Werpehowski, eds., (Georgetown University Press: Washington, D.C.), 1992, pp. 1-103. (Box 29)
    - Bibliography of published works, n.d. (Box 29)
  - Outler, Albert C.
    - Colleges, Faculties and Religion. The Educational Record: 1949, pp. 5-18. (Box 30)
    - Love Among the Eggheads. Danforth Fellow Conference, 1960, pp. 1-12.- (Box 30)
    - The "Platonism" of Clement of Alexandria. Journal of Religion: 1940, pp. 217-240. (Box 30)
    - Review of Reinhold Niebuhr: Prophet From American by D. R. Davies. New Haven Register, June, 1948. (Box 30)
    - The Mingling of Ministries, Digest of the Eighth Meeting of the Consultation on Church Union, Vol. VIII, March 1969, pp. 106-118. (Box 30)
    - Two volume set of Berlioz and the Romantic Century, by Jacques Barzun given to Outler when he left Yale, signed by YDS faculty and Dean (Box 6)
  - Pelikan, Jaroslav
    - After the Monks--What? (Louis H. Beto Memorial Lecture, The Springfielder, pp. 3-21)., n.d. (Box 30)
    - Historical Theology: A Presentation. Criterion: Spring, 1971, pp. 26-27. (Box 30)
    - Jozef Miloslav Hurban: A Study in Historicism. From: The Impact of the Church Upon its Culture, ed. Jerald C. Brauer, 1968, pp. 333-351. (Box 30)
    - The Marxist Heresy: A Theological Evaluation. Religion in Life: Summer, 1950. (Box 30)
    - Review of his book: More About Luther, by J. W. Heikkinen. Theology Today: July, 1959, pp. 284-286. (Box 30)
    - The Theology of the Means of Grace. Accents in Luther's Theology, pp. 124-147., n.d. (Box 30)
  - Peterson, Stephen L.
    - Articles
      - Collection Development in Religion and Theology in the Library of Congress (Paper presented at 35th Annual Conf. of ATLA. June 21-26, 1981, 12 pp.) (Box 30)
      - Documenting Christianity: Towards a Cooperative Library Collection Development Program. (Paper presented at 32nd Annual Conf. of ATLA, Jun 1978, 21 pp.) (Box 30)
      - From Third World to One World: Problems and Opportunities in Documenting New Christianity. Practice and Theory, Vol. 15, (1991), pp. 177-184. (Box 30)
      - Life, Begins at 40? The Institutional Context of ATLA - Presidential Address, ATLA Proceedings, 1987. (Box 30)
      - The More Things Change-The More Things Change: Theological Libraries in the 1990s, Theological Education: Spring, 1990, pp. 137-151. (Box 30)
      - Of Old and New Wine: Five-Year Report of the Divinity Librarian, 1982-1987. (Box 30)
      - On Capturing Greece: resources for new perspectives on mission history, Bulletin of the Scottish Institute of Missionary Studies, 1985-1987, pp. 2-6. (Box 30)
      - Patterns of Use of Periodical Literature. College & Research Libraries, Sep 1969. (Box 30)
      - Project 2000 Revisited, Theological Education, 1987 Jul, 12 pp. (Box 30)
      - Resources for China Mission Research: Resources in YDSL, International Bulletin, 1985 Jul, pp. 104-106. (Box 30)
      - The Subject Approach to Theology: An Alternative System for Libraries. (Paper presented before 31st Annual Conf. of ATLA, Jun 1977, 15 pp.) (Box 30)
      - Theological Libraries for the Twenty-first Century: Project 2000 Final Report, Theological Education, 20/3, Suppl., 1984. (Box 30)
      - The Theological Tasks of the Seminary Library. (Address delivered at the Garrett Evangelical Theological Seminary, Evanston, IL, Mar 3, 1983.) (Box 30)
      - Yale Divinity School Library: A Decade in Retrospect... Prospects for the Future, 1982 (Box 30)
      - Yale Divinity School Library: A Decade in Retrospect... Prospects for the Future, 1992 (Box 30)
    - Book Reviews By Stephen L. Peterson
      - Bonk, Jon, Ethiopian Orthodox Church: an Annotated and Classified Bibliography, 1984. (Box 30)
      - Roberts, W. Dayton and John A. Siewart (eds.), Mission Handbook: USA/Canada Protestant Ministries Overseas, 14th edition, 1989, in Missiology, January 1991. (Box 30)
  - Pope, Liston
    See Record Group No. 49.
  - Pope, Marvin
    See Record Group No. 135.
  - Porter, Frank Chamberlin
    See Record Group No. 119.
  - Powers, Charles William
    - American Civil Piety and the American Business Creed: The Demise of Complicated Synergism? The Changing Nature of American, 1973, pp. 32-44. (see also: Williams, Colin W.) (Box 30)
    - Response to "Reason, Rationalization and Foreign Policy" by David Little. (Box 30)
  - Rowthorn, Jeffery
    - Collegiality: An Initial Exploration. Theological Perspectives for the Practice of Collegiality in Union Theological Seminary. Union Sem. Quarterly Rev.: Summer, 1973, pp. 287-289. (Box 30)
    - Fifty Years after the Revolution. Union Sem. Quarterly Rev.: Spring 1969, pp. 247-263. (Box 30)
    - Peace Declared in Babylon. Union Sem. Quarterly Rev.: Summer, 1973, pp. 267-271. (Box 30)
    - The God Who Risked Christmas. Yale Divinity School Advent Preaching Series, December, 1981. (Box 30)
    - Hymn: Paraphrase of Psalm 148, tune "de Tar" by Calvin Hampton, 1973 (text 1974). (Box 30)
  - Ruether, Rosemary Radford
    - Anti-Semitism and the State of Israel: Some Principles for Christians. Christianity and Crisis: Nov., 1973, 4 pp. (Box 30)
    - The Collision of History and Doctrine: The Brothers of Jesus and the Virginity of Mary. pp. 93-105. (Box 30)
    - Continuing Reform after Vatican II. The Month: March, 1973, pp. 93-97. (Box 30)
    - Foundations of a Theology of Revolution. Unpublished notes. Sept., 1970, pp. 1-4. (Box 30)
    - The Free Church Movement in Contemporary Catholicism. pp. 41-52., n.d. (Box 30)
    - An Invitation to Jewish-Christian Dialogue--In What Sense can we say that Jesus was "The Christ"? The Ecumenist: Jan-Feb, 1972, pp. 17-24. (Box 30)
    - The Left Hand of God in the Theology of Karl Barth--Karl Barth as a Mythopoeic Theologian. The Journal of Religious Thought: 1968-69, pp. 3-26., 1969 (Box 30)
    - Male Chauvinist Theology and the Anger of Women. Cross Currents: Spring, 1971, pp. 173-184. (Box 30)
    - Male Clericalism and the Dread of Women. The Ecumenist: July-Aug., 1973, pp. 65-69. (Box 30)
    - The Messianic Horizon of Church and Society. Concilium: Jan., 1973, pp. 136-143. (Box 30)
    - Paradoxes of Human Hope: The Messianic Horizon of Church and Society Theological Studies: June, 1972, pp. 235-252. (Box 30)
  - Russell, Letty
    - An Ocean with Many Shores: Asian Women Making Connections in Theology and Ministry. A Report of the National Conference of Asain Women Theologians, (Northeast, U.S. Group), June 6-9, 1989, p.3. (Box 30)
    - Beginning From the Other End. Duke Divinity School Review, Vol. 45, (Spring 1980), pp. 98-106. (Box 30)
    - Bread Instead of Stone. Theologians in Transition, James Wall, ed., (Crossroad, 1981), pp. 177-184. (Box 30)
    - Called to Account. Ecumenical Review, Vol. 30, (Oct. 1978), pp. 369-375. (Box 30)
    - Curriculum Vita. 1986. (Box 30)
    - Discussion: Renewal in the Churches. Union Seminary Quarterly Review, Vol. 21, No. 3, pp. 333-338., n.d. (Box 30)
    - Education for Partnership. Reflection. Vol. 78 (April 1981), pp. 13-16. (Box 30)
    - Inclusive Language and Power. Religious Education, Vol. 80, (Fall 1985), pp. 582-602. (Box 30)
    - Issues in Liberation Theology: A Review Essay. Reflection, Vol. 83 (Winter 1986), pp. 11-15. (Box 30)
    - Partnership and the Future: God's Utopia. Bangor Theological Seminary Alumni Bulletin, LIV/1, Fall/Winter 1979-80, pp. 19-28., 1980 (Box 30)
    - Partnership in New Creation. American Baptist Quarterly, Vol. III (June 1984), pp. 161-171. (Box 30)
    - Tradition as Mission, Study Encounter, 1970, pp. 1-10. (Box 30)
    - Woman's Liberation in a Biblical Perspective. Concern, May-Jun 1971, 31 pp. (Box 30)
    - List of writings, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Salisbury, Edward E.
    - Inaugural Discourse on Arabic and Sanskrit Literature. (1843, pp. 3-51). (Box 31)
    - Memoir on the History of Buddhism. Am. Oriental Society: 1844, pp. 3-57. (Box 31)
    - Muhammadan Doctrine of Predestination and Free Will. J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1864, pp. 3-80. (Box 31)
    - Notice of the Book of Sulaiman's First Ripe Fruit. J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1865, pp. 1-82. (Box 31)
    - On the Identification of the Signs of the Persian Cuneiform Alphabet. J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1849, pp. 3-42. (Box 31)
    - On the Science of Muslim Tradition. J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1861, pp. 2-84. (Box 31)
    - Sketch on the Life and Works of Michaelangelo Buonarroti. New Englander: 1861, pp. 785-808. (Box 31)
    - On Some of the Relations Between Islam and Christianity. New Englander: October, 1876, pp. 752-771. (Box 31)
    - Translation of an unpublished Arabic Risaleh. J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1849, pp. 167-193. (Box 31)
    - Translation of two unpublished Arabic Documents...J. of Am. Oriental Soc.: 1849, pp. 259-324. (Box 31)
  - Sanders, Frank Knight
    See Record Group No. 122.
  - Sanneh, Lamin
    - Biographical Resumé, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Correspondence and Course Description, 1987 Mar (Box 32)
    - Research Writings and Publications (Box 32)
    - Christian Mission and the Western Guilt Complex: A Proposal (Box 32)
    - Mission, Translation and Cultural Change (synopsis of book) (Box 32)
    - Muhammed's Significance for Christians. Studies in Interreligious Dialogue, Vol. 1 (1991), pp. 25-39. (Box 32)
    - Prelude to African Christian Independency: The AfroAmerican Factor in African Christianity. Harvard Theological Review, Vol. 77, 1984, pp. 1-32. (Box 32)
    - The Accra Charter of Religious Freedom and Citizenship - introduction, 2012 (Box 16)
  - Schubert, Paul
  - Seitz, Christopher R.
    - According to the Scriptures: The Old Testament in the Passion Narratives. pp. 1-26., n.d. (Box 32)
    - The Divine Council Temporal Transition and New Prophecy in the Book of Isaiah. pp. 1-36. (Box 32)
  - Shedd, Clarence Prouty
    See Record Group No. 35.
  - Sneath, Elias Hershey
    - The Religious Basis of World Organization. Religious Education: Volume XIII, No. 2, April 1918, pp. 3-15. (Box 32)
  - Stout, Harry S.
    - The Crisis of Church History at Yale Divinity School. 1993, pp. 1-17. (Box 32)
    - James Davenport and the Great Awakening in New London (with Peter Onuf), Journal of American History, 1983 Dec, pp. 556-578. (Box 32)
    - Marsilius of Padua and the Nenrician Reformation, Church History, 1974 Sep, pp. 308-318. (Box 32)
    - Moral Philosophy in Colonial New England: From Early Puritan Piety to Perry Miller's Mistakes (review essay on Norman Fiering's Moral Philosophy at Seventeenth-Century Harvard: A Discipline in Transition and Jonathan Edward's Moral Thought and Its British Context), Fides et Historia, 1983 Summer, pp. 97-102. (Box 32)
    - Puritanism considered as a profane movement, Christian Scholar's Review, 1980, pp. 3-19. (Box 32)
    - Religion, Communications, and the Ideological Origins of the American Revolution, William and Mary Quarterly, 1977 Oct, pp. 519-541. (Box 32)
    - Rhetoric and Reality in the Early Republic. The Case of the Federalist Clergy, pp. 1-26. (Box 32)
    - University Men in New England 1620-1660: A Demographic Analysis, Journal of Interdisciplinary History, 1974 Winter, pp. 375-400. (Box 32)
    - Word and Order in Colonial New England, The Bible in America, 1982, pp. 19-38. (Box 32)
    - Bibliography of publications, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Streets, Frederick
    - Clergy as Counselor: A Question of Identity and Effectiveness. pp. 18-36. (Box 32)
    - The Violence of Our Time: address delivered before Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board of the American Baptist Churches, 1993. (Box 32)
  - Stroup, John
    - Political Theology and Secularization Theory in Germany, 1918-1939: Emanuel Hirsch as a Phenomenon of His Time (to appear in Harvard Theological Review) (Box 32)
    - Protestant Church Historians in the German Enlightenment.: 1) Correction copy - unpublished, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Protestant Church Historians in the German Enlightenment.: 2) Published copy, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Review of his book: The Struggle for Identity in the Clerical Estate (in American Historical Review, 1985, Vol. 90, p. 711.) (Box 32)
  - Stuehrenberg, Paul F.
    - A Guide to the Biographical and Bibliographical Sources for the Study of the Bible Before the Reformation. Journal of Religious and Theological Information, Vol. 1 (1993), pp. 17-28. (Box 32)
    - A Library Worthy of the School. A History of the Yale Divinity School Library Collections. 1992, pp. 1-65. (Box 32)
    - A Study of Acts Before The Reformation: A Bibliographic Introduction, Novum Testamentum, 1987, pp. 100-136. (Box 32)
    - Devout; Proselyte. Entries in The Anchor Bible Dictionary. Vol. 2 and Vol. 5. David Noel Freedman, ed., (Doubleday: New York), pp. 184; 503-505. (Box 32)
    - The "God-fearers" in Martin Luther's Translation of Acts, Sixteenth Century Journal, Vol. XX, No. 3, 1989. (Box 32)
    - The Medieval Commentary Tradition: The Glossa Ordinaria, Hugh of St. Cher and Nicholas of Lyra and the Study of the Bible in the Middle Ages. Journal of Religious and Theological Information, Vol. 1, 1993, pp. 91-101. (Box 32)
  - Torrey, Charles Cutler
  - Tweedy, Henry Hallam
    See Record Group No. 131.
  - Underwood, Kenneth
    - Problems Protestantism Faces in Contemporary American Society. (Paper read to the Divinity School Faculty, Dec. 7, 1950). (Box 32)
  - Vannorsdahl, John
    - Advent Preaching Series. Yale Divinity School, 1981, 5 pp. (Box 32)
    - In Memory of Roland Bainton. Reflection, Nov 1984, p. 7. (Box 32)
  - Vernon, Ambrose White
    - Christianity and Democracy. (1942, pp. 3-16). (Box 32)
  - Vieth, Paul
    See Record Group No. 59.
  - Walker, Williston
    See Record Group No. 51.
  - Weigle, Luther A.
    Weigle papers are at Sterling Memorial Library.
    - Bible Words That Have Changed Meaning, New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1955. (Box 32)
    - Jesus as Teacher, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Paul as Teacher, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Scholarship, Education, and the Bible, Address at the 16th triennial convention of the Cum Laude Society, May 1955. (Box 32)
  - Wenger, Tisa
    - "Female Christ and Feminist Foremother - the Many Lives of Ann Lee" in Journal of Feminist Studies in Religion, 18 no.2, Fall 2002, p. 6-32 (Box 16)
    - "Land, Culture, and Sovereignty in the Pueblo Dance Controversy" in Journal of the Southwest, 46, no. 2, Summer 2004, p. 381-412 (Box 16)
    - "'We are Guaranteed Freedom': Pueblo Indians and the Category of Religion in the 1920s" in History of Religions, 45 no. 2, November 2005, p. 89-111 (Box 16)
  - Williams, Colin W.
    - Articles
      - The Changing Nature of America's Civil Religion. (Aspen Institute of Humanistic Studies, 1973, 44 pp.) (Box 32)
      - Chautauqua Sermons - August 19-25, 1967. (Box 32)
      - The Church Listens to the World, Pre-Assembly Evangelism Conference, United Presbyterian Church USA, Boston, MA, 1966 May 17. (Box 32)
      - Citizenship, South Carolina, 1967 Jun. (Box 32)
      - Evangelism and the Ecumenical Movement, Tidings: Evangelism and Contemporary Issues, 1964 Spr. (Box 32)
      - The Institutions of the World, Look Up and Live (4 or 5 TV Programs), 1963. (Box 32)
      - The Mission of the Church, Article I, and The Church is for the World, Article II, The Church Herald, 1966 Fall. (Box 32)
      - The Myth of the City, The City Church, 1964 Nov-Dec (Box 32)
      - On Being Free for Christ's Work in the World, Protestant Churches and Reform Today, 1964 Fall. (Box 32)
      - Our Book - The Bible. (Our Faith Series, No. 1), n.d. (Box 32)
      - Our Master - Jesus Christ. (Our Faith Series, No. 3), n.d. (Box 32)
      - The Present Position in Evangelism, International Journal of Relgious Education, 1963 Fall. (Box 32)
      - The Professional Doctorate, Methods of the Berkeley Center and Some Theological Issues. (mimeo) (Box 32)
      - What Is Evangelism?, World Mission Newsletter, 1964 Oct. (Box 32)
    - Book Reviews by Colin W. Williams
      - Leeuwen, Arend Theodoor van, Christianity in World History (The Drew Gateway, 1966 Summer). (Box 32)
      - Outler, Albert C., John Wesley (The Christian Century, 1965 Apr 14 and The Journal of Bible and Religion, 1964 Fall). (Box 32)
      - Pelikan, Jaroslav, The Riddle of Roman Catholicism, (journal unidentified, n.d.). (Box 32)
      - Rose, Stephen C., The Grass Roots Church: A Manifesto for Protestant Renewal (Theology Today, 1967 Jan.)., n.d. (Box 32)
      - Winter, Gibson, Elements for a Social Ethic, (journal unidentified, 1967 Jan.). (Box 32)
    - Notes of Colin W. Williams
      - Miscellaneous, n.d.
    - Talks
      - "Evangelism Seminar", "Calvin & Reformation" - 2 reel-to-reel audiotapes (Box 16)
  - Wilson, Robert R.
    - An Interpretation of Ezekiel's Dumbness. Vetus Testamentum: 1972, pp. 91-104. (Box 32)
    - The Old Testament Genealogies in Recent Research. J. Bib. Lit.: 1975, pp. 169-189. (Box 32)
    - Early Israelite Prophecy. Interpretation 32, 1978, pp. 3-16. (Box 32)
    - From Prophecy to Apocalyptic: Reflections on the Shape of Israelite Religion. Semeia, vol. 21, (1981), pp. 79-95. (Box 32)
    - Prophecy and Ectasy: A Reexamination. Journal of Biblical Literature, V. 98, 1979, pp. 321-337. (Box 32)
    - Prophecy and Society in Ancient Israel: The Present State of the Inquiry. Soc. of Bib. Lit. Seminar Papers, 1977, pp. 341- 358. (Box 32)
    - This World - and the World to Come. Encounter [Christian Theol. Sem.], Vol. 38, No. 2, April 1977, pp. 117-124. (Box 32)
  - Wisse, Frederik
    - The Righteous Man and the Good Man in Romans v.7, New Testament Studies 19, no.1, Oct. 1972. pp. 91-93. (Box 32)
  - Wolterstorff, Nicholas
    - An Engagement with Kant's Theory of Beauty. pp. 1-21., n.d. (Box 32)
  - Wood, Richard J.
    - Christian Presence in High Education--Exploring some ambiguities, Keynote Speech, United Board Annual Trustees' Dinner, April 30, 2000. (Box 32)
  - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight
    - Address to the Professors in the Theological Department. (1861, pp. 7-25). (Box 32)
    - The Disciple Whom Jesus Loved. (n.d., pp. 1-23). (Box 32)
    - Discourse Commemorative of James L. Kingsley. (1852, pp. 3-16). (Box 32)
    - Historical Discourse, 150th Anniversary of Yale. (1850, pp. 3-78). (Box 32)
    - The Self-Propagating Power of Sin. (1868, pp. 3-16). (Box 32)
  - Wright, Henry Burt
    See Record Group No. 40.